okay so it's
Thursday September 26 and I'm going to
report on what we did yesterday and with
regard to Harbor and what we're going to
do today and really quickly so this
video should be under 15 minutes I hope
uh this is the video you're going to go
watch to catch up when you come in
Middle stream and I say go watch the
video and catch up so yesterday we set
out with a goal to get postcar
installed uh video coming yeah and we
did we got it we got it working and
installed um the problem is in fact I'm
going to put this down to the top after
we got it all install we finished the
build deploy and undeploy scripts um
which the the deploy and undeploy is
basically just g c apply dask using
customize and uh there's no template
there's no template substitutions
happening right now in customiz that'll
come later when we do Vault and stuff
like that still on the to-do list um but
we need to do that and then the undeploy
ridiculously easy that's just a a cube
CTL delete uh everything in that Nam
space so that those are done uh the
build the course is now done because
once we got the once we Chang the uh the
tag for postest from 13 to
16.4 uh the build is now you know
working and it's going in and that's
that all that stuff ready up no problem
uh at one point yesterday we got
everything working it was all working it
was it was ready um and then we spent
probably two hours trying to get uh the
web
interface in a way that could be
accessed and that's because this is a VM
running in Windows and I was I actually
had to redo mini Cube um uh I should
probably put that here so uh tried we
tried the Kimo
driver let me let me add this really
quick we tried the Kimu to um
the uh
nun uh and uh and the uh you know the
docker driver and I had to install a
bunch of prerequisites for that to do
none I had to install cctl and and all
this stuff I had I spent um uh uh spent
uh spent a lot of time installing
pre uh for uh drivers for miniu drivers
so uh we did we lost a lot of time on
that but I I feel like it was
educational um there's probably I mean
you can go watch the VOD for the next 60
days but if you really care to do all
that otherwise uh the we ended up
Landing uh on Docker U because of a
resource issue uh went with
Docker uh the docker
driver and we actually got that uh to
work
um I actually to now that I remember I
think we actually got the Kimu 2 driver
to work
both of them allowed us to install
everything but I'm trying to recall if
we ever had a successful version of the
whole thing with with all the stuff
being ready we saw there was at least
one time yesterday where everything was
installed and ready and there was no
need to disable
anything
um and uh by the way don't try to
disable Reedus we we disabled redis just
to see if we could get to work because
Reedus was the problem and we ended up
um
uh I I noticed it in the Valu file it
actually still needs to do caching so it
just does it in a different way and that
also failed so so we're having right now
we're stuck and that's what we're going
to do today right now we're we're stuck
on um on the reddis problem so figure
out why Harbor cannot access uh redus
and we did all of our you know we walked
to the V everything and the the errors
is that it can't Harbor can't create its
cash because it can't talk to redus and
this is a known problem it's like all
over the Internet we found all the
things but we couldn't we couldn't get
anything to do to fix it so that's where
we are we're stuck on that uh I don't
think it's resource related but it might
actually be related to the fact that
when we were trying to get all these
drivers to work um and we were trying to
get a way to view the harbor interface
uh the web interface we I did a lot of
stuff with
networking um I didn't do anything to
the system to Anton specifically that
explicitly that I can think of we
started up some SSH proxies and stuff
like that those things we re we rebooted
Anton so those should have all gone away
it is possible that we have screwed up
Anton and so Anton is the BM and so
somehow Anton is unable to do the
routing
um it is also possible that I brought it
up the first time and core DNS was not
up yet before I ran the install uh in
within kubernetes and so the second time
I did it let all the services for
kubernetes come up and I checked the
system you know services to make sure
they were all ready before I did any
apply and I applied it went in but then
from that point on it's having problem
getting red as it says it can't resolve
it and so I have a feeling it might be
DNS related um but I don't know so that
that's where we are and we're going to
be looking at that so um uh if I can't
get this working today the the I'm going
to try to just go through the steps
again and recreate it maybe I missed
something uh but just running you know
you know run the build script on the on
a fresh VM uh I've torn down and built
back up the the cluster of mini Cube
several times we gave it more resources
we bumped it up to I think six or seven
procs in the VM and then and then we
when we did Medi Cube we gave it uh 8
gigabytes or so 10 8 or 10 gigabytes um
so so that you know that's a thing and
um that was it we talked a lot about the
systems integration testing to to
establish whether it's you know working
or not the first point being can you
access the web interface and and you
know we we we spun our Wheels a lot on
that um I am fighting internally because
I am doing this for work I am fighting
internally a bunch of dialogue with
myself about trying this in our Dev
environment and seeing if it would just
work uh but I still feel like um the
issues with getting it in mini Cube and
stuff I still when I when I put it when
I when I transfer it over to work uh
some of this work it's not going to be
you know the exact same thing but
there's going to have to be ISO involved
and some other stuff's going to have to
change and come out and be added onto
that and um there's also the the
lingering um knowledge that I need to
get an actual lab running um if if I you
know mini Cube service mini Cube t
tunnel commands were not working of
course because it's running from a VM
and the VM just headless and it's
running in Windows so you know wanting
to start up your Rowser and stuff that
Min loves to do it couldn't do it uh so
you know that if if I'm I'm glad I'm
hitting all those problems because that
is actually going to influence my home
lab decision so tune in on Fridays for
the home lab thing if you want to um but
that has really definitely solidified my
decision to make sure I have my own
cluster uh number one and uh you know
get kbm working on there and uh to put a
uh a some sort of desktop environment on
it and you might ask well why would you
do that um I'm no I'm not a fan of Linux
desktop but by having a Linux desktop on
my home lab when I need to do a quick
and dirty test of this kind of thing I
can VNC into it and I can run mini Cube
you know as sort of God intended and it
will pop up my browser and it will show
me and I can forward the services and do
everything that makes Mini Cube great
for really quick and dirty testing of of
development of of Kap development stuff
like that so H so so that these those
hurdles that I hit with mini Cube are
actually good because I actually really
like mini Cube lately the the latest
version of mini cube is got a lot of
things in including watching every
single thing it does it I just found
about this yesterday somebody told me it
like puts it all in a log and so most of
my development I I will maintain an
individual cluster uh to run certain
applications that I want but to tell you
the truth most of the applications
development I'm going to be doing is
probably going to be standing up mini
Cube um I don't use kind anymore um kind
kind is a great tool it is it's still a
great tool but it can't hold a candle to
mini Cube these days um all the stuff
that mini the add the add-ons for mini
Cube are just insane we we add added the
Ingress ad on yesterday so I'm a huge
fan of Min Cuba and MBA has gotten so
good in my opinion that with a kbm back
driver and mini Cube you really don't
need much more than that if you're an
API developer I I'm honest to God I and
I think you're you know that's kind of
the sweet spot where mini cube is trying
to to Target so so that's the takeway
for today come join us if you want to be
part of the of the of the debugging
process and everything uh otherwise I'll
report back tomorrow uh people have been
asking about where go programming and
all that stuff uh if and when I do that
I'll be sure to make a video about it
but um we it that is generally going to
be what I do after this Harbor stuff is
done I'm back to back to a bunch of go
coding so stay tuned there will be go
coding here there will be home lab stuff
on Fridays there will be uh IRL things
but I'm not pushing the the IRL and the
yoga vids anymore uh I'll I'll make the
occasional IRL clip or something like
that but that stuff you don't need to
worry it's not coming in the the videos
for YouTube so thank you YouTube see you
later